Finding Aid for Arthur H. Vandenberg Papers, 1884-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Reorganization bill
(15) FDR to AHV re: item veto [FDR letter - see New York Times dateline 3/10/41] - FDR does not think Constitutional amendment necessary, that Congress could include the power within an appropriation bill - clipping and Congressional Record following pages
(19B) - AHV for across board price, wage freeze
(20B) - Report on Col. Hoyt Vandenberg
(23) -- "The Labor Mess" AHV note 3/27/42
(23) note, no title, dated 4/21/42 - on Willkie's "victory" for internationalism at Republican National Convention Meet. [PPSVP 30]
(26) -- "June 4, 1942" AHV Note Declaration against Bulgaria, Romania, and Hungary. PPSV p. 31-32
(26B) - Jay G. Hayden "Churchill's Peace Union"
(29) newspaper AHV mild attack of appendicitis
(33) - AHV Fla. Canal sp. Congressional Record
(34B) - 7/21/42 thank you letter from Harold Ickes
(37B) - newspaper AHV, jr. becomes Lt.
(46) - AHV speech on Social Security [brief AHV note on 39B]
(51) text of AHV speech (in newspaper) probably Oct. 31 or Nov. 1 From Grand Rapids, broadcast over Mich. radio network, then late by station WOOD
Volume XV, Nov. 1942 - Oct. 1943
(2B) -- [c. Nov. 1942 Prof. Jas K. Pollock endorses AHV proposal to lower voting age to 18.
(3B) - AHV letters opened and excerpted by censors
(5B & 6) - AHV says won't run in 1944
(6) - AHV criticizes Willkie and others who criticize Ickes deal in No. Africa with Darlan
(10) AHV letter to Mark Sullivan 12/29/42 re: charge of pre-Pearl Harbor interventionists -- SIGNIF
(13B) - Dec. (?) 1942 AHV asks trials to fix blame for laxity at Pearl Harbor
[Begin 1943]
(14B) - Trying to oust Tugwell
(22) -- letter from H.M. Morgenthau commending AHV for participation in radio program re: income tax
(23B) - Mark Foote article on AHV Senate sp supporting extending Lend Lease
(26) - Picture of Special Committee on Post-War Economic policy and Planning
(33) - Apr. 19, 1943 AHV note (and message from MacArthur)
(38) - May 3 dateline. Jay Hayden article on AHV efforts and case for MacArthur
(38B) - Time 5/17/43 on same as above
(41) - Congressional Record pages. AHV sp. on tax bill
(44B) - Article by AHV "Why Not Deal Congress In?" Coronet July 1943 pp. 3-7
(45B) - 6/15/43 letter from Procope of Finland. Recalls AHV got debt postponements for 41 & 42. Procope notes Finland has now paid next installment due.
(48) - Jack Bell (AP staff writer) "Republican Accord Seen" Not Republicans will try to agree on statement re: post-war foreign policy. Austin identified with internationalist wing, AHV middle of roader, Taft as inclined to make more reservations than AHV re: collective action. No Date [June 43?]
(49B) - Articles on V-White Resolution. Jay Gould. Also NY Time headline but article missing.
(53) - Submitted resolution ,referred to SFRC, to check the draft agreement for UNRRA recently published by State Department to see whether should be sent to Senate for approval as a Treaty
-- AHV statement
-- Alberson named in statement
(57) - Newsweek (Aug. 30, 1943) on NNRRA correspondence; state dept. changed language so could submit; go to both houses for majority vote -- Acheson and AHV said to be peacemakers
(61B) - Articles on Mackinac conference
(62) - AHV introduces Mackinac Committee report and some editorials into the Congressional Record Appendix Sept. 14, 1943
(64) - R.O. Woodruff in House inserts AHV Sept. 22 Blue Network Speech on Mackinac Charter into Congressional Record. Congress Record pages here.
(65) - Letter from Thos. Dewey Sept. 16, 1943 - commends AHV for conciliating role at Mackinac
(66) - Letter from Gov. Edward Martin of Penn. re: Mackinac
(68B) - Letter Oct. 4, 1943 from P.I. Pres. Manuel L. Quezon
(69B) - Opposes school subsidy bill
(72) - from Congressional Record - pages with AHV statement on Connally Resolution - in contrast to reprint floor discussion is included
(76b) - AP article AHV (& Landon) reject idea that Republican and Democratic parties have identical foreign policy planks in 1944.
(80) - AHV Note "The Mud-Smear Press" - re: Marshall Fields II newspaper "PM" in N.Y. Misrepresented AHV on soldier vote
(81B) - AHV questions to Stimson and Knox re: an officers accepting nomination and election.
(84) - AHV notes "The History of the First Attempt to Commit Our Post-War Objectives" - see pages 84 to 101.
Volume XVI, (late 1943-) 1944
(9) - Nov. 22, 1943 from C.J. Harlan F. Stone; wouldn't want to serve on a U.S. War Ballots Commission
(12) Colliers article "Why I Am for MacArthur" Feb. 12, 1944
(15B) - letter from Dean Acheson considerable on UNRRA in this Scrapbook
(35B) - New York Times dateline 4/28/44 AHV to London Daily Mirror
(35B) - Postwar Organization committee of 8 senators establish
(38) -- "AHV" note "The MacArthur Boom Bursts" 4/30/44: AHV blames Rep. A.L. Miller of Nebraska who published both to & from the General - critical FDR administration. MacArthur renounces nomination - AHV doubts could have been nominated anyway in of Dewey momentum - AHV says his support of MacArthur probably cost Convention Temporary Chairman (& Key noter)
(41) - Telegram from George Romney thanking AHV for passage of Murray Bill
(44) - AHV Note May 11, 1944
(44B) - AHV letter to Cordell Hull 5/3/44 (photo copied)
(45) - AHV note May 19, 1944
(45B) - AHV note May 23, 1944
(46) - AHV note May 26, 1944
(46) - AHV note May 29, 1944
(46B) - AHV note May 29 cont'd
(47ff) - several articles on Hull-Senators talks - M. Childs, Foote, G. Ross, etc.
(51) - newspaper article by Jas L Wright, no date quote from AHV funny speech to "J. Russell Young School of Expression"
- (51B) letter complimenting speech from Admiral Ernest J. King
(54) - June 9, 1944 AHV Note re: invitation to attend Bretton Woods conference [see PPSU 109]
(55B) - On Senate floor June 13, 1944, AHV - Hatch exchange over Republican foreign policy
(61) - AHV Note "Chicago National Convention - June 26-29, 1944"
-- tells of getting foreign policy plank pretty much settled before hand - then of his efforts to stop one Wisconsin delegate from making a speech to nominate MacArthur.
(65) - 6/20/44 letter from John Foster Dulles
(66) - AHV note "The G.I. Bill of Rights" - says he one of original sponsors, when going was rough; all senators ended up sponsoring it.
(70) - Aug. 1 dateline. Arthur Krock column, "Recalls Truman Criticism" Sub: V. says Missourian in '41 blamed Ross for delays in Defense Program
(73) - 8/24/44 White House invitation for AHV, his note: "The first since 1933" [What about when British King there and FDR insulted AHV?]
(77) - AHV letter to Hull Aug. 29, 1944 (see next entry--part of content similar) - letter quoted PPSV p. 117-
(78) - AHV note "Friday, July 25, 1944" - but a penciled note signed by Jee Morres says this must be wrong. Must be August 25. Appear under date of August 25 in PPSV pp. 115-116.
(79) - Congressional Record Tear sheets. AHV says in floor debate [Bushfield of S.D. has spoken] that the Dumbarton Oaks Conference can only set down the rules under which all delegates to the council of the new organization from all countries shall operate and vote. It has no jurisdiction over instructions that any individual country shall give to its own delegate in respect to whether or not he shall be a full agent in voting. n.d.
(79b) - Reston dateline Sept. 6: New York Times Security Planners Look to Senate
(80B) - Lippmann "Dumbarton Oaks: The American Problem" (Sept. 14, 1944) White House favors separating question of Germany & Japan from general ID question says FDR can (as Wilson could have) get Senate approval to act without referring to Congress to police Germany and Japan But can't, does not need, a 'blank check'. Quotes letter from AHV agreeing.
(81) - AHV puts Lippmann column in Congressional Record Sept. 15 1944
(83) - Sept. 22, 1944 letter from Cordell Hull
(85) - Newspaper articles on authorship of FDIC
(87) - Article on Mrs. AHV - picture in Red Cross uniform
(91) - AHV note - Nov. 24, 1944 - on meeting with Stettinius & Pasvolsky - see PPSV pp. 121-122.
(91B) - Congressional Record floor. Praises retiring Hull & incoming Stettinius
(95) - 12/1/44 note of thanks from retiring Hull
(99) - AHV note "The Palestine Run-Around"
(99B) - AHV note Dec. 21, 1944 - on conference in New York of Republican Party leaders. Dewey quoted by AHV as saying did not want the nomination in 40, 44, 48. - Willkie and Landon have died in last-month. According to few items in this Scrapbook, AHV did not want to be minority leader. Letters indicate that in Oct. '44 AHV was in hospital for awhile, resisting pneumonia, with bronchial problems. The pictures in the 1945 Scrapbook are the first in which he begins to look old. Cause-effect?
Volume XVII, 1945
(5) - 1/10/45 Speech Congressional Record
(6) - (also 3B) Krock columns date lines Jan. 10, 11 p.16 Jan. 15
(9B) - Lippmann column
(11B) plus before and after. Administration pleasure revealed by putting AHV speech on radio office of War Information-overseas
- THAT JAN. 10, 1945 SPEECH REALLY CREATED A SENSATION.
(20) - LIFE editorial
(21B) from Bernard Baruch regarding speech
(23) - New Republic
(27B) Reston on Stettinius reaction - dateline Jan. 17, 1945
(30B) - Reston article New York Times dateline Feb. 3, 1945 two-thirds back Vandenberg
(32) - Congressional Record tear sheets: AHV has placed in record -- "Extension of Remarks" - Speech he delivered in Detroit Feb. 5 -- Correspondence with FDR re: appointment of AHV as delegate
(43) - 2/15/45 to FDR
(43B) - 2/28/45 from FDR
(44) - 2/26/45 from FDR
(44B) - 3/1/45 to FDR
(45) - 3/3/45 from FDR
(45B - AHV accepts San Francisco post
(46) - dateline 3/21 New York Times Dulles refuses Conference post
(46B) - Cordial note from H.A. Wallace
(47) - article AHV "Let's Try to Prevent World War III" Saturday Evening Post [posted in Scrapbook in such fashion that no dates show, can't all be read]
(55B) - Reston dateline 4/1/45 New York Times "Vandenberg urges changes for Fluid World Council"
(55B) - also 4/1 dateline New York Times text of AHV memo to State Dept. proposing 8 amendments to Dumbarton proposals "Text on p. 11" New York Times
(56B) - Newspaper article re: GA votes agreement at Yalta: 3 for U.S. & USSR, 6 for Great Britain. AHV expresses disapproval
(57B) - White Puts in Congressional Record Baltimore Sun editorial on AHV San Francisco views
(59B) - Newspaper dateline 4-9 quote of AHV Senate speech (Apr. 8 or 9) before leave for San Francisco
(61) - AHV notes on FDR death
-- also Congressional Record tear sheet of AHV remarks on FDR death
(61B) - Letter 4/12/45 from Senator W.H. White
(64) Official Commission as delegate from Harry S. Truman, with seal, etc. 4/17/45
(64B) - from Stettinius 6/23/45 commending AHV work at San Francisco
(66) AHV's "ticket" signed by Alger Hiss. UN polar projection of globe with olive wreath, appears on it!
(67B) - from HST 4/18/45 thanks for message of 4/13
(68B) - AHV on Time cover 4/30/45
(71) - 4/18/45 Stettinius letter to AHV
(72) - Drew Pearson column. Notes AHV is No. 1 U.S. delegate at San Francisco. Notes Connally rivalry.
(78) - Bad cold sends AHV to bed for a couple of days
(37B) AHV (says newspaper article) is for a single U.S. airline abroad
(46) -- "Dulles refuses Conference Post" 3/21/45 dateline
(83B) New York Times, dateline June 1. AHV accepts implied-power language regarding 6 A review of treaties rather than specific language to that effect.
(86B) - Berryman cartoon "There are other Signers, Too." UN charter is on a table, showing signatures of 5 U.S. delegates. By the table stand in "invisible" figures of FDR & Wilson. In background columns of "invisible" U.S. G.I.'s & sailors march by.
(89) - Congressional Record tear sheets AHV U.N. speech 6/29/45
(92B) Mark Foote interview "Compares Frisco Pact with old League Newspaper, no date right after UNCIO
According to New York Times obituary index, Mark Foote died age 75 in 1957. See NYT July 27, 1957. Wrote for N. The interview on Booth Newspaper Syndicate of Mich., p. 92B ff., did not appear in either Detroit News or Detroit Free Press. I checked them May 29, 1971. Grand Rapids Press
(93) - Foote interview #2: "Veto Clause Powerful Weapon for U.S."
(93B) - Foote interviews #4 & 5. #3 not included?
-Two of the Foote Interviews:
"14th" - in this newspaper -- "Answers Objections to Frisco Charter"
"5th" - in this newspaper -- "Cites Charter as Aid to Peace with Russia"
Foote's columns appeared in Ann Arbor News (editorial always on p. 4) - but in this series not the one on Charter as Aid to Peace with Russia
"1st" article of series July 2 - gives 5 reasons
"2nd" article of series July 3 - on veto
"3rd" article of series July 4 - trusteeships [not in Scrapbook]
- article of series July 6 - disagreements with Bushfield
- Article of series July 9 - contrasts covenant & chart
"last" Article of series July 10 - expects greatest opposition when get to implementing legislation
I checked Ann Arbor News June 30-Aug. 2, 1945 for Foote Peace in Charter as aid to U.S.-U.S.S.R. Relations & didn't find. Were other, non-series, articles on AHV
June 29 - on AHV Senate speech
June 28 - AHV contribution at San Francisco
June 27 - on AHV and San Francisco conference
July 26 - on Senate debate
(95) - Newspaper text of AHV Det. Eco. Speech on U.N.
(100B) -- [July 19, 1945?] Congressional Record sheet. AHV - brew exchange regarding Poland.
(102) - Begin floor debate on Charter - Congressional Record sheets
(101B) - Newspaper Chicago Daily Tribune July 18, 1945 very critic of AHV current views with "T of a Tradition"
(105B) - Nelson Rockefeller telegram July 30, 1945
(106B) - letter from Grew July 30, 1945
(107) - letter from Ickes no date
(109) - Newspaper text (New York Times Aug. 6, 1945) of AHV letter (Aug. 5, 1945) to Byrnes - also Reston column
(114) - AHV article New York Times Magazine Sept. 16, 1945
(115) - AHV note: "The Communists - on The Daily Worker"
(124) - Hayden Oct. 19: "Crowley Hails V. as Best Friend of FDIC"
(129) - AHV speech (Congressional sheets, "Raise the Iron Curtain")
(138) - AHV notes 12/10/45 on Senators meeting regarding A-Bomb with Byrnes before Moscow trip 12/11/45 Senators with Truman became disturbed at Byrnes plan
(139B) - Newspaper dateline Dec. 19 - AHV one of 5 General Assembly Delegates for U.S.
(140) - Dec. 18 telegram from Aba Hillel Silver - thanks for help Senate Palestine resolution
(140B) - AHV - 12/21/45 to Harry S Truman
(141) - HST letter to AHV - 12/21/45
(142) - Reston article - dateline Dec. 19 re: upset of senator re: Byrnes A Bomb plans - meeting before Moscow trip
(144) - New York Times article, dateline Wash., Dec. 28, by C.P. Trussell. "Truman assures Congress Atom Secret will be kept till Safeguards Operate"
(136B) - undated, unidentified newspaper article on British loan Senators wonder if Russia next; Byrnes says doesn't need, if asks he'll say no. AHV "impishly" asks how affect relations with U.S.S.R. if let British put hand in Treas. but not Russians
Volume XVIII, 1946
(p. 1) - AHV: "I was on diplomatic missions 213 days in 1946 as follows:
Jan. 5 to Feb. 20 - London, Gen. Assembly of U.N.
Apr. 23 to May 18 - Paris, Council of Foreign Ministers
June 14 to July 14 - Paris, Council of Foreign Ministers
Aug. 24 to Oct. 17 - Paris, Peace Conference
Oct. 20 to Dec. 16 - New York Council of Foreign Ministers and General Assembly, United Nations"
(2) - Harry S Truman letter to AHV
(3) -- "Byrnes puts End to Atom Bomb Row" New York Times dateline Jan. 9, 1946. V. is satisfied. No secrets given without "adequate security arrangement"
(8) -- "Redeployment Speed is urged by V" from London, New York H Tribune dateline Jan. 12. U.S. soldiers in London have performed a get-us-home demonstration. AHV meets. Sympathetic -- wires Ike.
(9b) - AHV sick with cold. Won't make planned fact-finding trip to Berlin. Dulles will go alone. [Dulles and AHV are thick at London -3A]
(11 & 11b) - good photos
(12b) - War hero, "Arthur E. Wermuth" may run against AHV. Another clipping says civilian nurse in Manila asks annulment of marriage with him - she didn't know he married in States. He denies knowledge. Manila, dateline Jan. 29, A.P.
(13) -- "Vandenberg" by Blair Moody - magazine article, unidentified -Says AHV one of dozen senators called to White House summer night 1939 when FDR said wanted neutrality acts repealed then for would keep Hitler from attacking. Borah said his inform better than State Dept. and would be no war anyway. If war, then can repeal, the senators said. "In 1940 V's view started to change." Nix FDR, but o.k. aid short of war to Great Britain. --a right decent article
(14b) - note from staff re: Republican National Committee desire for AHV speech tour. Places, dates, fees
(15) - Gerald Movius, "That Man V - unidentified and undated. article. Looks like Parade or New York Times Magazine
(17) - Feb. 27 Senate speech after return from London
(18b) - Lippmann, "A Sour Note on Eloquence"
(20) - Krock on 2/27/46 speech Dateline 2/28/46. "Behind Mrs. Vandenberg's Broad Phrases"
(21b) - Letter from Herbert Lehman thanking AHV for help on UNRRA authorization and appropriation. No date
(23) - Front cover picture on LIFE 3/11/46. [articles often postulate that Sec. Byrnes speech on Feb. 28 to Overseas Press Club in New York City, forced by AHV's speech day before, influenced by it]
(23b) -- "National Affairs" Time 3/11/46 on Byrnes and AHV speeches. Notes AHV didn't include Byrnes in list complimented. Note AHV especially impressed by Bevin.
(24b) - New Republic comment on 2/27/46 speech. Date 3/1/46. Positive
(26b) - 3/18/46 letter Byrnes to AHV
(34) - AHV works out compromise on A-control bill
(37b) - gets Colliers award for distinguished Congressional service Gives his $10,000 to Red Cross
(39b) - 4/12/46 to AHV from AA Vandegrift, General, U.S. Marine Corp congratulations on Colliers award
(42b) - Forrestal to AHV 4/17/46 congratulations on Colliers award
(46) Richard Wilson, "Vandenberg - Man in the Middle" Look Vol. 10, No. 1 May 14, 1946
(58) Jay G. Hayden, "Russia Asks Billion Loan as U.S. Tightens Strings" May 24, 1946 dateline
-- $90,000,000 loan to Poland was approved, made contingent on Yalta, Potsdam pledges.
-- Now loan held up.
-- Suggests there will be similar strings on Soviet loan. Numerous remarks in these Scrapbook pages about new-formed coop. between Burnes/Connally - AHV, new unity in AFP. Paris widely seen as a turning point.
(65b) - Hoyt Vandenberg made head of "Central Intelligence"
(74) John Gunther, "Inside Vandenberg" Liberty July 13, 1946 - picture shows AHV sitting on a stump, looks like walking cane he's holding
(74b) - Members of House and Senate, polled by Pageant voted AHV as (1) "ablest" (2) "most effective speaker" (3) "best grasp of foreign affairs"
(78) - Newspaper piece on conference committee impasse re: atomic control and military role
(84) - Excerpts V J day address
(86) - Text American Legion Address
(97) - Begin controversy over Wallace New York Speech
(98) - Marquis Child's, "Behind Wallace's Speech" Detroit Free Press, Sept. 17 -- Says Wallace had, in HST office, read what he thought pertinent excerpts. --were interrupted. --HST got impression it mainly a pal speech endorsing Lehman and Mead. ---When will Clayton say speech and probable consequences, was only 30' until Wallace to speak in Madison Square Gardens. -- too late to get W. and say get indigestion: the speech or parts of it had already moved over news tickers
(101b) - 1936 Radio "Debate" - Krock article dateline Oct. 29, due to Dems using FDR voice in 146 elections. Says P.R. man Hill Brackett conceived idea and AHV selected as interrogator.
(102b) - AHV got 68% vote
(105) Joseph and Stewart Alsop "Taft & Vandenberg" - Life Note division between domestic and International Relations. See possible trouble in Taft's desire to move in to foreign policy area - Say Taft will see significance of recent primary defeats of - LaFollette, Wheeler, Shipstead, Nye (all conspicuous isolationists)
(111b) - 51 Republican senators now in Senate as of Jan. 1947
(112b) - Byrnes to AHV commendations re: Paris Conf. Oct. 12, 1946
(119) - AHV gets name inscribed in Golden Book of the Jewish National Fund.
(123) - Alfred Kelly "Vandenberg: Politician Turned Statesman"
Volume XIX, 1947
(1) - Newspaper article says, 4/day holiday in Grand Rapids -- first vacation since Pearl Harbor
(2) - AHV will be Pres. pro tempore
(3) - American Mercury article, Jan. 1947. Vol. LXIV, No. 277 "Vandenberg of Mich" by Fred Rodell
-- says Av 6' 1", 200 lbs. - attributes AHV changes, including one in foreign policy: "not until WWII was almost won that Vandenberg had his historic change of heart." (p. 7)
-- This article includes stuff from earlier articles, also that appears in later, especially Cover: Tompkins also - Generally negative though tone tries to make it appear otherwise.
(4b) - Krock, dateline Jan. 6, re: Baruch retirement, maintenance of his firmness line; AHV support.
(8b) - Harry S Truman letter to AHV, Jan. 9, 1947, - thanks re: action (extremely speedy) on Marshall appointment (a move to demonstrate foreign policy unity ... waived hearing on nomination. - Newspaper article re: Byrnes resignation
(10b) - AHV wants Bilbo barred
(11b) - Hayden, dateline Jan. 11, on Cleveland speech by AHV. AHV promise Marshall support, but dissents re: China
(12) - Newspaper text Cleveland speech
(13b) - Lippmann column on Cleveland speech. Comments tone, etc. -Goes on to suggest Marshall disengage self from detailed negotiation of Council of Foreign Ministers, which not a good instrument.
(24b) - Marquis Childs on why AHV won't, shouldn't, go to Moscow with Marshall
Note: Marshall becomes Sec. of St. almost simultaneously with AHV chairman
(25b) - Alsop & Alsop, on Republican Presidential candidates. AHV in fine health, but "a minor heart trouble"
(26b) - Esther Tufty article on Arthur, Jr.
(27b) - Reston piece, dateline Feb. 4, on AHV effort with Senator Millikin, plus Acheson and Clayton to work out a compromise on reciprocal trade bill that won't split the Republicans, will inject isolationism into Economic valve of foreign policy too. AHV now spoken of a supporter. AHV for putting in an "escape clause"
-- last paragraph says AHV won't go to Moscow, though he and Connally have been asked.
(27b) - also New York Times piece dateline, Feb. 4. AHV and Connally not go to Moscow now, maybe later
(31) - Newspaper text of AHV speech to Republican Convention: in Grand Rapids Press. Sat. Feb. 8, 1947
(32b) - Herald Tribune, Feb. 15 dateline, AHV may oppose big cut of HST Army and Navy budgets by Budget Committee
(33b) - Langart, dateline Washington, Feb. 14 AP on AHV speech given to Michigan State Chamber of Commerce for Congressional delegation
(35b & 3Tb) - AHV support seen as critical to Lilienthal confirmation. Taft and White oppose. Feb. 22, New York Times piece says AHV can give no Republican votes
(41) - Dulles will be an adviser in Moscow
(41b) - New York Times, Feb. 25, on Tariff, etc.
(45) - 3/1/47 AHV letter to HST wanting Taft in secret meeting. AHV wrote reply on bottom
(46 & 47) - Newspaper pictures of Congressional group leaving White house after conference on Greek situation
-- Good bit in newspaper articles on AHV-Taft differences, possible split.
(48b) - Newsweek 3/17/47. "Vandenberg and Son's Co." -- notes heavy load as senator, pro tem, Chairman. - AHV Jr.'s role discussed - AHV no longer walks to and from Hotel - Capitol
(49b-51) - newspaper stories. Re: request aid to Greece and Turkey, AHV makes big deal of complete and open hearings. Asks all Republicans to be fact finders, to submit questions for San Francisco R.C. to submit to Admin. witnesses.